This material is made available to you by or on
NOTE CONF
behalf of the University of Melbourne under section 113P of
the Copyright Act 1968.
NOTE CONF
It may be subject to copyright.
For more information, visit the university copyright website.
NOTE CONF
OK, uh, good morning and uh welcome to week eight.
This week we're talking about security, education, training and awareness.
NOTE CONF
Um, And most of all the, uh, Levers that you
can pull in an organization of all the formal controls
NOTE CONF
and informal controls and administrative controls.
This particular control is the most, you might say informal.
NOTE CONF
It is directed towards behavior change of individuals in organizations.
It strives to achieve behavior change, but it struggles to
NOTE CONF
be effective because of one key barrier.
What, does anybody want to guess what that barrier might
NOTE CONF
be?
What is the key barrier that you face if you
NOTE CONF
are trying to create behavior change?
Comes with a C.
NOTE CONF
Sorry?
Culture, culture.
NOTE CONF
Organizational culture is the key barrier that you have when
you're trying to create behavior change because as the famous
NOTE CONF
management, management consulting phrase goes, culture, what is the phrase?
Culture eats strategy for breakfast, right?
NOTE CONF
So your strategy to create behavior change is going to
be frustrated and it's going to be sabotaged by the
NOTE CONF
culture of the organization.
This is a huge, huge problem and the primary reason
NOTE CONF
why the vast majority of security culture programs fail.
They fail before they even start.
NOTE CONF
So we're gonna talk about CETA, security, education, training and
awareness.
NOTE CONF
And this week, you are studying the relevant Canvas module.
You've, you've got prescribed reading, not much because there's not
NOTE CONF
much in the book about it.
Um, answer questions on Canvas, attend the workshop.
NOTE CONF
I believe you have a quiz.
In the workshop, you'll have Q&A and then you'll be
NOTE CONF
doing an exercise where you'll be creating posters for CETA
and I hope you really enjoy the exercise.
NOTE CONF
Every year, we have some fantastic posters coming out.
Um, I really enjoy looking at them.
NOTE CONF
The tutors always bring them to the tutors' meeting and
discuss the really creative approaches that students come up with
NOTE CONF
to uh build posters to create behavior change.
So, um, 5 key objectives.
NOTE CONF
For this week, appreciate why an effective CETA strategy is
critical against social engineering attacks, but in general.
NOTE CONF
Dis distinguish the attributes, objectives and methods of education, training,
awareness.
NOTE CONF
So how do you do it?
Identify the key steps in a program and how they
NOTE CONF
form a control.
Identify at least 3 critical challenges to a successful program.
NOTE CONF
Appreciate the relationship between CETA and organizational culture.
But before we actually get into the content, let's do
NOTE CONF
this really quick exercise.
So, you are the new CETA lead for a large
NOTE CONF
organization of 12,000 people.
OK, so, this is your position.
NOTE CONF
And you have been told these behaviors exist already in
the organization.
NOTE CONF
The annual module, the security training module is clicked through
video muted.
NOTE CONF
Right, audio muted.
The passwords, passwords are shared inside Teams to avoid Remembering
NOTE CONF
them Phishing simulations get forwarded as a joke, not reported.
Doors are held for anyone, even if they're carrying a
NOTE CONF
laptop bag.
Security says whenever security says no, you're not allowed to
NOTE CONF
do blah blah blah.
The real, the real effort amongst the people is to
NOTE CONF
figure out a work around it.
Yeah.
NOTE CONF
And the last person who who reported the security violation.
was blamed for it, right?
NOTE CONF
So, clearly, examples of a culture going wrong, I want
you to spend about 1 to 2 minutes to write
NOTE CONF
down 3 to 5 things that you would do as
the lead for CETA to create a more positive security
NOTE CONF
culture in the organization.
OK.
NOTE CONF
Write them down.
We're gonna come back to it at the end of
NOTE CONF
the At the end of the hour.
OK.
NOTE CONF
Anybody wanna volunteer a couple of ideas you might have?
But these are some of the things that you might
NOTE CONF
do.
As the head of CETA in the organization.
NOTE CONF
Yeah, um, so anonymity for the reporter.
Whistle whistleblower state and say, OK, OK.
NOTE CONF
And uh tokens for logging sessions open and device stuff
like some sort of a bank address stuff so that
NOTE CONF
uh only once.
Person will be responsible with their specific device and that
NOTE CONF
access to the.
So that's a general security control.
NOTE CONF
How is that a cultured, how is that a behavioral
Influence listening to you.
NOTE CONF
That's why I'm trying to, OK, OK.
And another one will be we will be more, uh,
NOTE CONF
job.
OK, so you, you wanna create training videos that are
NOTE CONF
more specific to the role rather than generic.
OK, interesting.
NOTE CONF
Any other ideas?
Yes.
NOTE CONF
At least so they know how.
Sorry, what was the first thing, first part of the
NOTE CONF
sentence?
What are you gonna do?
NOTE CONF
A drill.
Also you wanna use a drill to create like a
NOTE CONF
real life situation that people can sort of see.
OK, interesting, yeah.
NOTE CONF
That's very easy to, yeah.
Uh, like, uh, like.
NOTE CONF
Like specific training sessions, yeah, each units.
You The second one with the uh like.
NOTE CONF
A measurable target, OK.
Objective, yeah, yeah, yeah.
NOTE CONF
It, uh, We can give incentive or And we work
for the union our department that already.
NOTE CONF
Oh, OK, so reward the units that behave the best
or perform the best, OK.
NOTE CONF
From, formalize it to uh Formalized into policy.
And create enforcement around behaviors.
NOTE CONF
OK, very good.
Interesting ideas, interesting ideas.
NOTE CONF
Let's talk about um we'll go through some of these.
Hopefully, by the end of the hour, when you come
NOTE CONF
back and revisit these, you'll have a deeper richer, a
richer view of what is possible, and then you can
NOTE CONF
evaluate your own ideas and come up with more.
SoITA, again, Just to reiterate, another control sits in the
NOTE CONF
security control category, and it serves the same purpose.
You have to remember that CETA isn't some unique unicorn
NOTE CONF
sort of thing.
It, the policy, risk strategy, CETA, they're all trying to
NOTE CONF
do the same thing.
They're trying to protect your asset against your threat.
NOTE CONF
Right, that is the key thing.
And in doing so, the CETA controls that you come
NOTE CONF
up need to be very much oriented towards the risk
scenarios that you have identified that are going to be
NOTE CONF
impactful against your assets.
So Education, training and awareness, it's important to distinguish the
NOTE CONF
three of them.
That's one of the first things that people miss when
NOTE CONF
they talk about training and culture in an organization, they
kind of fold the three together and they don't really
NOTE CONF
distinguish them.
Education is really about in-depth knowledge, and it's really aimed,
NOTE CONF
it's really focused on the security leaders who are developing
the programs.
NOTE CONF
If they don't know why they're doing it, if they
don't know what is the strategic objective of security in
NOTE CONF
the organization and how it's aligned to the business, they're
not going to be able to develop a program that's
NOTE CONF
going to, you know, help the business achieve its security.
Goals.
NOTE CONF
So the education piece is aimed, needs to be aimed
at the right people, which is the security leadership.
NOTE CONF
The training piece is a much more broader one, which
is really about devoting or attributing delivering skills to your,
NOTE CONF
your user base or your end users.
In this case, it might be, how do I run
NOTE CONF
an anti-virus on my computer and remove all the viruses.
That's a skill.
NOTE CONF
And you need to train people on how to use
what whatever pieces of software are available, how to run
NOTE CONF
it, how to read a log report, how to know
the viruses are gone or not, and blah, blah, blah.
NOTE CONF
That's a skill.
So, Education separate, skill training separate, and then there's awareness,
NOTE CONF
which is really just about trying to get information at
the front of your mind, right?
NOTE CONF
There are 3 fundamentally different things and there's a table
that I would personally spend a lot of time staring
NOTE CONF
at, and I have, and I suggest that you do
as well, and this is the table.
NOTE CONF
So, it actually, it actually pulls out all the fine
distinctions between Education, training and awareness.
NOTE CONF
And these fine distinctions really matter because when you can
separate the three tools, you can then learn how to
NOTE CONF
use the right tool for the right purpose.
Otherwise, you use a very coarse, blunt tool to try
NOTE CONF
to deal with your behavior change.
You have 3 tools.
NOTE CONF
Education, training and awareness are three different tools.
You need to respect and understand each one of those,
NOTE CONF
each one of them separately, and their advantages and disadvantages,
there are pros and cons, what differentiates them, and then
NOTE CONF
apply them in the right context to get the maximum
effect.
NOTE CONF
So let's start with awareness.
Awareness targets the what are, you know, Security is important
NOTE CONF
when you've got employees in your organization that are doing
their regular work.
NOTE CONF
Security might be the last thing on their mind.
If you try to get security in front of mind.
NOTE CONF
This is what awareness does.
It doesn't try to train them to do anything.
NOTE CONF
It doesn't try to explain the why.
It doesn't try to tell them how to do anything.
NOTE CONF
It's just, hey, remember security.
Don't forget security.
NOTE CONF
It's important.
And a very common mechanism to create awareness are these
NOTE CONF
posters that are on the walls of your organization or
the mugs that have security-related messaging on or a pen
NOTE CONF
with messaging on, these are just triggers to remember security.
So security awareness is about just remembering on an informational
NOTE CONF
level to expose the people repeatedly to the importance of
security, and it's really channeled through media like posters and
NOTE CONF
like trinkets and so forth, and it's usually a true
or false thing.
NOTE CONF
Is security important or not?
Or you know, should I put my passwords up or
NOTE CONF
not?
Should I do this or not?
NOTE CONF
This is what awareness is about.
It's very short term memory.
NOTE CONF
It's not long term or medium-term memory.
Now, compare that with training, which is really answering the
NOTE CONF
how question.
How do I do something security related?
NOTE CONF
Here, again, as I said, anti-virus software, how to run
it, how to know that there are viruses on your
NOTE CONF
computer or not, whether they've been removed or not.
This is a skill and it's about practical instruction.
NOTE CONF
It's actually delivered mostly through workshops, where you Bring a
practical thing that needs to be done in front of
NOTE CONF
the audience and you train them on how to do
it.
NOTE CONF
That is the problem solving technique, and it is very
much about intermediate memory.
NOTE CONF
And then lastly, education, which is what we're doing here,
right?
NOTE CONF
We're answering in this forum, the why question.
Why do we always look for the why or the
NOTE CONF
underlying reasons why things happen the way they do.
And so it's theoretical instruction theory is what we're trying
NOTE CONF
to get to concepts, deep concepts, profound insights, theories that
explain behavior, and they underlie everything.
NOTE CONF
Without a good theory, right, you can't really understand the
real world.
NOTE CONF
And that might sound like a contradiction.
People go, Oh, theory means impractical.
NOTE CONF
No, no.
A theory is a generalization of a lot of instances.
NOTE CONF
So if there's 10,000 instances of why something happens the
way it does, a theory will try to encapsulate that
NOTE CONF
and explain that to you so you don't have to
experience 10,000 instances, you know why things.
NOTE CONF
Work the way they do.
That's why a theory is very powerful, and that's what
NOTE CONF
we try to give at the education level targeted towards
chief information security officers, security leaders is the theory, which
NOTE CONF
is how the security works.
For example, the triplet model is a kind of a
NOTE CONF
theory.
It's a very powerful theory because it says there are
NOTE CONF
only two things to worry about assets and threats that
define the problem.
NOTE CONF
And then the scenarios need to be mapped out and
if you can map those out accurately and completely and
NOTE CONF
control them, then you have security.
That is a very powerful theoretical paradigm which encapsulates security
NOTE CONF
in any situation.
So you don't have to have a life of 10,000
NOTE CONF
years and experience all the different types of security challenges.
You know how to deal with them, right?
NOTE CONF
That's what the theory is there to do, and that
is long term learning.
NOTE CONF
So education, training and awareness are your three big mechanisms.
What is a good CETA program look like?
NOTE CONF
Well, it definitely is not obsolete.
It uses whatever methodologies, whatever mechanisms that are recent, modern,
NOTE CONF
um, and it trains people in their context.
So this is very well known actually that if you
NOTE CONF
take people outside of their organizational learning environment and you
put them in a training workshop, for instance, and you
NOTE CONF
bring them back to their organization, whatever they learned in
that training workshop, their organization is going to resist.
NOTE CONF
Right?
It's called training tourism.
NOTE CONF
You go to a training program, and you learn wonderful
things, you feel amazing, you go back to your organization.
NOTE CONF
And all the behaviors that you were told not to
do, your organization continues to do because inertia is very
NOTE CONF
powerful.
And because you live in that organizational ecosystem where you
NOTE CONF
have relatively little power, unless, of course, you are board
of directors, CEO, etc.
NOTE CONF
you basically end up falling in line with everybody else
and forgetting everything that you have been trained.
NOTE CONF
Not necessarily forgetting, but it is You know, it is,
it is actually removed from you.
NOTE CONF
It's pulled out of you, right?
You just sheer frustration and sheer, um, uh, uh, I
NOTE CONF
don't know what the right word is, but you just
give up in that organization because they are not going
NOTE CONF
to change.
You are one person and they may be 10,000 people.
NOTE CONF
You will not change 10,000 people, the 10,000 people will
change you.
NOTE CONF
Right?
So that situation, it makes it really, really challenging for
NOTE CONF
CETA, which is why doing training inside the organization environment,
within that context, amongst the people is the way to
NOTE CONF
actually transform the organization.
If especially if that is your objective.
NOTE CONF
It, uh, workshops target usually a small number of people
at a time, Broad spectrum training tends not to work.
NOTE CONF
Small focused tailored training which is very relevant to the
people who are in the classroom tends to work better
NOTE CONF
than broad spectrum training where it's not clearly relevant to
the people and it runs periodically, not just at one
NOTE CONF
time.
So you need to continue to be trained and to
NOTE CONF
be reminded because reminders keep, make things stick in your
head as opposed to if you just get, if you
NOTE CONF
start an organization, you get trained and then 20 years
later, you don't remember ever being trained, let alone what
NOTE CONF
was inside the training.
Um, 7 steps to a CETA program.
NOTE CONF
If you're developing a CETA program, generally, you follow this
this approach.
NOTE CONF
What's the scope?
What's, what are my goals?
NOTE CONF
What is the behavior change I'm trying to affect?
What is, and this for me is where most, most
NOTE CONF
people, most programs fail, right?
They don't study the culture, just like with policy we
NOTE CONF
said last week, if you don't understand the existing culture,
you can't change it, because you don't know what to
NOTE CONF
change.
In order to be effective, you need to know what
NOTE CONF
is the current behavior in the environment, why does it
exist?
NOTE CONF
How did it come about?
Why has it been sustained for so long?
NOTE CONF
What is keeping that culture, that behavior alive?
What is the behavior I want to see?
NOTE CONF
How am I gonna make that transformation?
How am I gonna get people to move from what
NOTE CONF
they're doing now to what I want them to do?
And you have to respect the current behavior.
NOTE CONF
You can't disrespect it and say, oh, people, they just,
they're just so stupid, right?
NOTE CONF
They, when I show them the light, they will all
change.
NOTE CONF
No, you're the stupid person.
They're all doing things for a reason.
NOTE CONF
There is a reason why you don't know the reason
yet.
NOTE CONF
First of all, before you do anything in CETA, find
out why that behavior exists.
NOTE CONF
Once you discover that behavior's reasoning, why the under, what
are the underlying motivations drivers for it, only then will
NOTE CONF
you be able to tackle those drivers.
If you don't, and you just look at the surface
NOTE CONF
behavior and say, I'm going to change that, good luck
with that, right?
NOTE CONF
Not gonna happen.
I'll give you an example.
NOTE CONF
One of our Malaysian PhD students, she did her PhD
on why employees share sensitive organizational information.
NOTE CONF
On Facebook.
This is 10 years ago when Facebook was more of
NOTE CONF
a thing than it is now, right?
1015 years ago, right?
NOTE CONF
And she, she wanted to know why do Malaysian employees
share private information about the organization on Facebook?
NOTE CONF
Like, why would you do such a thing, right?
And she started by interviewing security managers across Malaysian organizations.
NOTE CONF
And all the managers were very downright condescending about it.
They were saying, oh, employees, our employees are horrible.
NOTE CONF
They don't read the policy, they don't understand, they don't
respect the organization.
NOTE CONF
They don't do blah, blah, blah, they don't do blah.
They do, they had a whole list of reasons why
NOTE CONF
it was so bad, this culture, and that they just
need to enforce harder and have more severe penalties.
NOTE CONF
Then, she interviewed the employees and asked them, why are
you doing this?
NOTE CONF
And she found something really interesting.
The employees realized that when they tried to contact their
NOTE CONF
supervisors through email and ask them to assist them or
to give them direction on their work, that their employees
NOTE CONF
would never answer email, but they would answer if they
posted on Facebook.
NOTE CONF
Right?
So there was a culture in the organization where their
NOTE CONF
supervisors would respond if they were tagged on Facebook, but
would not if they were using company emails.
NOTE CONF
And they didn't have time.
They, they had a lot of deadlines that they had
NOTE CONF
to meet, and they couldn't wait around for their supervisors
to respond and get around to emails.
NOTE CONF
So they started to follow them on social media and
begin to tag them and to communicate on social media.
NOTE CONF
And you know, if you work in, you know, or
you have lived or you operate in that part of
NOTE CONF
the world, Indonesia, Malaysia, etc.
WhatsApp is huge.
NOTE CONF
It's how people get work done and I never use
WhatsApp, until I started, you know, actually doing work in
NOTE CONF
Malaysia and I began to, I got infected, and then
I started using WhatsApp for everything, and now my research
NOTE CONF
team contacts me on WhatsApp here, which we would never
do before.
NOTE CONF
And we actually discovered with the national cyber strategy in
Malaysia, that the National Crisis Management is running through WhatsApp.
NOTE CONF
People are actually communicating with each other in a national
crisis situation on WhatsApp, which is an insecure platform.
NOTE CONF
So we started to pull that into our case studies
when we were training the National Cyber Agency, you know,
NOTE CONF
case studies where everything was going well until the attacker
got onto WhatsApp and realized everything that they're doing, right?
NOTE CONF
And so it's only when we use case studies like
that that the people go, oh, maybe we shouldn't.
NOTE CONF
Use WhatsApp.
Maybe we should use something more secure.
NOTE CONF
But of course there's a problem there, right?
If you move to Signal or something else, there's an
NOTE CONF
accessibility problem.
Not everybody wants to use Signal, right?
NOTE CONF
WhatsApp is just universally available, right?
So there we go.
NOTE CONF
Anyway, so number one is a real problem.
You need to understand what is driving behavior.
NOTE CONF
If you keep on just say, oh, we're going to
make enforcement harder, penalize people with more, you know, severe
NOTE CONF
penalties, etc.
you're missing the point.
NOTE CONF
You might be actually sabotaging the organization's productivity.
Because there may be a reason why people are doing
NOTE CONF
what they're doing, you need to find that out first.
But once you've done that, once you've done your research
NOTE CONF
piece and figured out why culture is the way it
is, then you can start saying, OK, what's the scope
NOTE CONF
of my program?
What do I want to do?
NOTE CONF
What are the objectives of my program?
What's the behavior change I need to see?
NOTE CONF
Then you identify who's gonna do the training.
Find the staff.
NOTE CONF
Who's my audience?
Is it the whole organization?
NOTE CONF
Is it parts of the organization?
Am I going to treat the whole organization as one
NOTE CONF
unit, or am I going to break it up into
pieces?
NOTE CONF
How am I going to do this, right?
What are my target audiences?
NOTE CONF
And then motivate management employees?
Why would they change their behavior?
NOTE CONF
Like what's in it for them?
I know what's in it for me.
NOTE CONF
I want to meet my KPIs.
It's not enough to say it's good for the organization.
NOTE CONF
Who are you to say, a security leader that is
good for the organization?
NOTE CONF
Right?
It's notoriously hard to train a CEO, by the way.
NOTE CONF
Imagine a security leader trying to train a CEO.
If you watch that video, James Bormann talks on our
NOTE CONF
LMS about when he was CIO of this Australian organization,
and he had to train the CEO about how to
NOTE CONF
handle information in airports, and trams, and taxis, because he
was a a.
NOTE CONF
Very outgoing mobile CEO, right?
That's a, that's a very typical problem.
NOTE CONF
A security leader, especially if they're in the technology operations
division, again, security is a cost center, not a revenue
NOTE CONF
generator.
They are not going to be respected by the business
NOTE CONF
leader, like who are you to tell me what to
do, right?
NOTE CONF
So that is a power differential.
You have to figure out how am I going to
NOTE CONF
overcome the power differential in my organization.
So why would people do this and then administer the
NOTE CONF
program, whatever that looks like, and then it's not a
one-shot.
NOTE CONF
It's not a one shot approach, right?
You have to maintain the program, and then you have
NOTE CONF
to find some way to evaluate whether you're meeting your
objectives or not, and then change the program.
NOTE CONF
You can't assume that when you first run your program,
it's going to work.
NOTE CONF
It's going to have to go through.
It's going to have to evolve and adapt and change
NOTE CONF
and create a fit with the organization.
Only when it adapts to the organization's culture, is there
NOTE CONF
any hope of actually being successful.
Who's gonna do the training, internal staff, or do we
NOTE CONF
hire an external training team that specializes in it?
Specialist trainers or non-specialist trainers?
NOTE CONF
Training team that trains the whole organization on everything, so
they know our people and our culture or a security
NOTE CONF
team that doesn't know anything about the organization but knows
security.
NOTE CONF
For a hybrid team that knows the organization and knows
security.
NOTE CONF
Right?
Is it internal people?
NOTE CONF
Is it external people?
Can we afford to pay for a specialist training team?
NOTE CONF
To come in and do this.
And are we going to do, are we going to
NOTE CONF
deal with all end users in one big broad spectrum
approach?
NOTE CONF
Are we going to break them down into units and
then train each unit separately?
NOTE CONF
Do we, do we treat general end users differently, differently
to management people and executive leadership, and how about the
NOTE CONF
board?
Do we train everybody?
NOTE CONF
Do we train them at the same time and who
do we start with?
NOTE CONF
Do we start training top down, or do we start
training bottom up?
NOTE CONF
And there is this big problem in high power distance
index societies versus low power distance index societies and high
NOTE CONF
power distance index societies.
Especially in industry, there's this feeling the board feels they
NOTE CONF
don't need to be trained, like, uh, what do you
mean I need to be trained?
NOTE CONF
Do you mean that I don't know enough, right?
Why and, and, and who should train me?
NOTE CONF
I'm only gonna accept training if somebody of my level
trains me.
NOTE CONF
Otherwise, I'm not going to allow some, you know, commoner
come in and, you know, train me.
NOTE CONF
This is a very common attitude.
People will not.
NOTE CONF
So actually, to be able to train a board of,
you know, a director in a prestigious organization, you can't
NOTE CONF
just waltz in, even if you are the world's renowned
expert in it, right?
NOTE CONF
You have to be invited in, and then you have
to be recognized for your credentials, you have to be
NOTE CONF
seen to be providing value.
And even after all of that, and you produce your
NOTE CONF
fantastic training program, you turn up and what happens?
Everybody's asleep.
NOTE CONF
Right, they don't really care.
And what they've gone through 10 trainings on security, and
NOTE CONF
the last 9 of them were given by technical people
who talked about penetration testing, and the board just went,
NOTE CONF
uh, damn, not another one of those, right?
So, there's a whole culture around how do you, how
NOTE CONF
do you, how do you actually meet the people at
the right level in order for them to Understand what
NOTE CONF
you're saying.
And then, and then on the right hand side of
NOTE CONF
this slide, Not everybody's a novice, you're going to come
across people who consider themselves to be experts, and you
NOTE CONF
have to distinguish between people who are actual experts and
people who perceive themselves to be experts, right?
NOTE CONF
Because perception is a very powerful thing.
If somebody says or thinks to themselves, I'm an expert,
NOTE CONF
what do you think they're going to do when you
start training them?
NOTE CONF
What do you think they're gonna do?
It's not a trick question.
NOTE CONF
You've never had this experience, we've come into a room,
tried to present something to somebody, and they've said, hey,
NOTE CONF
I'm an expert.
Right?
NOTE CONF
You don't know what you're talking about?
No, I haven't had that wonderful experience.
NOTE CONF
It's beautiful.
You have to be prepared for that, right?
NOTE CONF
So you'll meet people who will say, you don't know
what you're talking about, or I have more experience than
NOTE CONF
you, or uh maybe you should do something with your
life, right?
NOTE CONF
Um, so that's one, that's the, uh, the people who
will just tell you on your face, and then there's
NOTE CONF
other people who will think it but won't say it,
but both, in both cases, they're gonna shut off, they're
NOTE CONF
not gonna learn anything that you say, right?
So you have to think about how am I going
NOTE CONF
to deal with novice, novices, people who are actual novices,
people actually intermediate level, people who are actually advanced level,
NOTE CONF
and then, how do I deal with people who perceive
that they are novices, not really a big danger, but
NOTE CONF
who perceive themselves to be experts, and they're going to
be really difficult.
NOTE CONF
And especially if they're in a powerful position in the
organization, where they're setting culture.
NOTE CONF
Like their CEO, board of directors, etc.
they create culture around them.
NOTE CONF
If they don't change the outsized influence they have, that's
going to be very hard to address.
NOTE CONF
OK, delivery methods.
So how do we get our message out there?
NOTE CONF
Many ways, one on one, sit with your individual and
speak to them one on one, like the CEO or
NOTE CONF
a board of directors.
That's one way to show respect, one way to train
NOTE CONF
them, get them outside of the general environment, but still
inside the organization and train them personally in a formal
NOTE CONF
class.
Community learning Bring the whole department together, so everybody in
NOTE CONF
the department is in the classroom, and then you can
run case studies about what's going on in that department.
NOTE CONF
Right, and they will talk amongst each other and you'll
get to learn what the real culture is in that
NOTE CONF
department.
Computer-based training, which is what most organizations do, driven really
NOTE CONF
by compliance, and I would say highly ineffective in general,
because people keep, they have to do 10,000 training, online
NOTE CONF
training modules a year, and they just shut their mind
off and they just point and click and copy and
NOTE CONF
paste and.
Try to get it done as soon as possible.
NOTE CONF
Low cost distance learning and web seminars.
If you have a mobile workforce and you can't face
NOTE CONF
to face train them, then you might have to run
online training.
NOTE CONF
User support groups, very powerful, cuts across the organization, self-organizing
groups where people are just helping each other and they're
NOTE CONF
motivated to learn more, to do more because they are
self-organizing.
NOTE CONF
Very powerful and untapped resource that you have, um, on
the job training.
NOTE CONF
People who are demonstrating what they're doing, and you are
demonstrating how to do what they should be doing, very
NOTE CONF
powerful, and self-study, again, non-computerized self-study, which I think doesn't
exist anymore today, maybe last century, not this century.
NOTE CONF
You have a lot of mechanisms, you have posters, you
have banners, you have newsletters, you have bulletin boards, you
NOTE CONF
have brochures, you have flyers, you have videos, you have
lectures, you have trinkets, you've got a whole range of
NOTE CONF
different, you know, concrete.
Digital physical things that you can employ in your training
NOTE CONF
program.
The security newsletter is very powerful because it, um, well,
NOTE CONF
I would say it's a very cheap tool that you
can put a lot of information in and blast broadcast
NOTE CONF
across the organization.
So if people are already engaged, it's a useful way
NOTE CONF
to keep them engaged.
If they're not engaged, it's not going to do anything
NOTE CONF
for you.
But there's a lot of things that you can put
NOTE CONF
in that newsletter which you can see on your right,
which is summaries of key policies, news articles, key security
NOTE CONF
events, blah blah blah, how to do X, how to
do Y.
NOTE CONF
A poster, very powerful way of keeping people aware.
On the walls, you can have posters that say loose
NOTE CONF
lips sink ships, things like that, reminding people not to
say things that are confidential, uh, putting up, you know,
NOTE CONF
don't put up your password on your machine or blah
blah, just reminders.
NOTE CONF
can be useful, but only useful if you keep changing
the posters.
NOTE CONF
If you keep the posters up there for a year,
people will notice that the first time, think, oh, how
NOTE CONF
cute, and then they will just completely zone out, right?
So you have to keep the posters interesting and keep
NOTE CONF
changing them and keep referring to them in the newsletters,
in the training, in the policies.
NOTE CONF
They have to be fully integrated in your program.
They can't just be left on the wall, disconnected and
NOTE CONF
orphaned from your security program, right?
It won't work if the message is not clear, and
NOTE CONF
they have to be relevant to what the people are
talking about.
NOTE CONF
Now, the last 1015 minutes, I want to talk about
a really interesting Telstra case study that uh one of
NOTE CONF
our PhD students did.
Um, before I get to that, I want to talk
NOTE CONF
about this behavior change model.
It's a really powerful model.
NOTE CONF
It explains.
Why people follow direction.
NOTE CONF
Right, and there's 3 reasons, and they go in steps.
So, level 12, level 2, to level 3, and the
NOTE CONF
general wisdom, general understanding is that you go from level
1 to 2 to 3, don't jump to level 3.
NOTE CONF
Level 1 is compliance.
People follow rules to avoid punishment.
NOTE CONF
OK, so if I tell somebody something to somebody, they
will follow because they're afraid of the punishment.
NOTE CONF
Now, first things first, um, it's very generational, as we
said last week, generation.
NOTE CONF
X, Generation Z, Generation B will be different to the
baby boomers.
NOTE CONF
Just because the baby boomers will follow direction doesn't mean
everybody will, so you have to remember that bit first.
NOTE CONF
Secondly, compliance has two factors to it.
If you say, Hey, if you don't do blah, if
NOTE CONF
you do blah blah, something's going to happen to you,
two things have to happen for them to actually believe
NOTE CONF
that.
Number 1, this punishment has to be severe enough that
NOTE CONF
they care.
And number 2, they have to be certain that the
NOTE CONF
punishment will actually happen.
If you are If you are not enforcing that penalty,
NOTE CONF
people will not respect it, and they will not change
their behavior.
NOTE CONF
If the penalty is too light and people don't care
if you do it or you don't, they will not
NOTE CONF
change their behavior, right?
Those are two things that have to work in terms
NOTE CONF
of compliance.
But compliance really is about following rules to avoid punishment
NOTE CONF
and compliance, if you, as soon as you remove the
penalty.
NOTE CONF
The behavior returns back to what it was before.
So it's a very superficial mechanism to create behavior change,
NOTE CONF
and not one that I'm particularly fond of, by the
way.
NOTE CONF
Identification people follow a practice because of a relationship.
They respect somebody.
NOTE CONF
Somebody's really cool or fantastic or a leader or whatever,
and because they do it, I'll do it because I
NOTE CONF
want to be in the in-group.
And this is a very powerful technique, right?
NOTE CONF
So if there's amongst in your workplace, if there's a
leader, somebody everybody looks up to, and they are very
NOTE CONF
careful about security, you'll be amazed at how everybody will
suddenly become careful about security.
NOTE CONF
And if they're not careful about security, everybody will not
be careful about security.
NOTE CONF
They create culture around them, and that identification is a
really powerful way to create conformance and behavior change.
NOTE CONF
You walk into an organization, you might have had a
really poor behavior around passwords, but if you see people
NOTE CONF
in the organization, especially your team leader, who's very careful
about something, you will try your very best to mimic
NOTE CONF
that behavior and fall in with the crowd.
That's identification.
NOTE CONF
And then internalization is when people do something because they,
it's part of who they are.
NOTE CONF
It's just in their DNA, right?
I'm a security leader.
NOTE CONF
I'm supposed to be behaving in a, actually this is
a really bad example because security leaders are really bad
NOTE CONF
in their personal security.
But generally, if you find people who believe very strongly
NOTE CONF
in something, let's say you're gym freaks, right?
They have this image of themselves that I'm this amazing,
NOTE CONF
you know, Olympic level athlete, and they will go to
the gym 23 hours every day.
NOTE CONF
It's a crazy commitment that most people will not be
able to do, but there's some people who will just
NOTE CONF
do, and they'll just do it every day, and they'll
do it for decades.
NOTE CONF
You'll see people in their 70s who say, I've been
training 23 hours a day for 20 years.
NOTE CONF
How do you do that?
It's because they've built up this, it's in their, their
NOTE CONF
system.
They're in their DNA.
NOTE CONF
They see themselves in the mirror as somebody who fits
this profile, and then they do everything that fits that
NOTE CONF
profile.
Right, you just follow that profile.
NOTE CONF
And this is a very powerful technique as well.
But it requires you to create that DNA in the
NOTE CONF
organization.
An organization that believes that it is special because it
NOTE CONF
is a secure organization, and we just do things this
way in the organization.
NOTE CONF
Everybody that will fall who comes into the organization will
suddenly become like that, right now, The story with Telstra.
NOTE CONF
Until 2014, their awareness capability was entirely compliance focused policy,
standards, annual mandatory training.
NOTE CONF
Cyber was considered to be an IT issue and it
was owned by security operations, and so a cyber influence
NOTE CONF
team was set up in 2014.
This is an old study now, it's about 10 years,
NOTE CONF
12 years.
Uh, and that they agreed the cyber was about people,
NOTE CONF
and so they moved it from IT to business risk
and focused on changing behavior rather than raising awareness.
NOTE CONF
So it's not just, hey, remind people about security.
No, no, no, no, it's not, it's now change behavior.
NOTE CONF
That's the focus.
Who was in it, 6 people, none of them technologists,
NOTE CONF
thank God, that's probably why it worked.
Right?
NOTE CONF
Put technical people in there and they can't think outside
of that technology box.
NOTE CONF
Who is in it, a poli that was led by
somebody with a political science degree.
NOTE CONF
That explains a lot, and a career in stakeholder relations,
two former technology journalists, a designer, a UX specialist, and
NOTE CONF
an administrator.
So they pulled the team together, who don't look like
NOTE CONF
anything you would see in a technology operations group, and
they did this.
NOTE CONF
They started a champions network.
It was opt-in, so volunteer based, every level and every
NOTE CONF
department could be part of it.
Champions were chosen on enthusiasm rather than seniority, no pay,
NOTE CONF
no promotion, no set time commitment.
It's demanding, but You can volunteer, you don't have to
NOTE CONF
be part of it.
And so people, why did people be part of it?
NOTE CONF
Because they wanted to see themselves as cyber champions.
It was an image thing.
NOTE CONF
They wanted to be cool, and so they joined and
they volunteered more hours and were more enthusiastic than had
NOTE CONF
they been paid for it.
What's in it for them?
NOTE CONF
So they asked people, always, all these champions went around
and asked people why they would do what they would
NOTE CONF
do, um, what the incentives, what incentives they would like
to see.
NOTE CONF
And they started off at about 50 people and I
think they went up to 700 people.
NOTE CONF
No, so it started off with 5 people, and they
went up to 700 people across the entire organization, word
NOTE CONF
of mouth being the way that they actually spread.
Information about their existence and you could basically go to
NOTE CONF
the security team and say, hey, um, We want a
briefing for our units, and they would arrange that, uh,
NOTE CONF
drills, they would arrange red team, you know, people, penetration
testers to come in and demonstrate things.
NOTE CONF
They would even spend time with the security operations center
and watch them and maybe give them, you know, information,
NOTE CONF
advice, etc.
etc.
NOTE CONF
So, Before we get back to our list, which we
will do in a minute, culture eats strategy for breakfast.
NOTE CONF
Why are CETA programs so effective?
Because culture eats strategy for breakfast and because people don't
NOTE CONF
have time.
They're very busy.
NOTE CONF
You have to compete for their attention, and one program
doesn't fit everybody.
NOTE CONF
You have to come up with different programs.
You have to keep changing them.
NOTE CONF
You have to tailor them to different people's roles.
Compliance is really not a good reason for behavior change,
NOTE CONF
but it's the reason that most CETA programs run.
And if you want to do it properly, it's expensive,
NOTE CONF
and security is a Cost center, not a revenue generator.
So there's no money, which is why you don't have
NOTE CONF
these elaborate programs to do these sorts of things.
OK.
NOTE CONF
So, now, Let's go back to our list.
You've heard for about 45 odd minutes, all the different
NOTE CONF
things that can be done and why they need to
be done.
NOTE CONF
I want you to go back to your list, the
one that you wrote and query it and ask yourself,
NOTE CONF
what would you change?
What level were you aiming at?
NOTE CONF
Who was your audience?
Why would they do what you thought?
NOTE CONF
And do you think that your initial ideas were effective?
And would create the behavior change you wanted.
NOTE CONF
So have a think about it and then tell me
what you think.
NOTE CONF
What changed in your list?
If anything.
NOTE CONF
Volunteers?
Yes.
NOTE CONF
That's listed what you have walked into is passwords are
shared by teams to upload.
NOTE CONF
that that the OK.
So is that on your list?
NOTE CONF
No.
What was on your list?
NOTE CONF
Actually I was thinking of like a baseline assessment.
OK, OK, so, so if you were doing a baseline,
NOTE CONF
if you were thinking, hey, I'll run a baseline, you
know, training program, one of the things that you might
NOTE CONF
take away from today's, you know, conversation, our presentation is
that maybe a baseline isn't the solution for everything, that
NOTE CONF
it works for maybe, you know.
Good passwords, but it doesn't work for the vast majority
NOTE CONF
of the things that you need to do.
Yeah, so it needs a nuanced approach, right?
NOTE CONF
Training is nuanced.
Yeah.
NOTE CONF
Any other Great to say.
Let's go back to the ones that we heard in
NOTE CONF
the beginning.
So can we, we had 2 people there talked about
NOTE CONF
their initial list.
Can you give us your list again?
NOTE CONF
Go.
Real life drills.
NOTE CONF
So that turned out to be actually a really good
idea, right?
NOTE CONF
Because real life drills, as we saw, um, can be
very powerful, especially if the drill is designed to address
NOTE CONF
a specific problem that is relevant to the the group
that's in the room, right?
NOTE CONF
So something that they're doing, and you show a skit
where the person, you don't say don't do this, you
NOTE CONF
show them somebody doing the same thing.
And then what the consequences, and then you show them
NOTE CONF
maybe what they could have done differently, and what, how
they could avoid that consequence, and that becomes a very
NOTE CONF
obvious way of sending a message.
OK.
NOTE CONF
What was your second?
Identify employee motivation, yup, so that's still very much relevant.
NOTE CONF
What was #3?
So Uh, OK.
NOTE CONF
OK.
So, introduce, uh, cyber behavior as a KPI in, into
NOTE CONF
your promotional criteria, right?
So you can't, this is very often actually done, people,
NOTE CONF
you know, people, lots of organizations have cyber in their
KPI, um, what do you think are the OK, what
NOTE CONF
do you guys think about this idea of putting cyber,
good cyber hygiene or whatever, you know, behavioral indicators into
NOTE CONF
somebody's KPIs?
What do you think about that idea?
NOTE CONF
Do you think it's gonna work?
It depends.
NOTE CONF
Yeah, I think it probably depends on the culture of
the organization.
NOTE CONF
It can be used against that individual, like, oh, we
don't want to promote this person.
NOTE CONF
Oh, let's blame it on their poor cyber behavior, or
if they do something that we go, Oh, that's not
NOTE CONF
good cyber behavior, we just use that now as an
excuse, whereas other people with the same behavior are getting
NOTE CONF
promoted.
Yeah.
NOTE CONF
So, uh, the big question is, how does the, what
is the organization's attitude and their culture around promotions?
NOTE CONF
And if the culture is a very positive culture, then
maybe it might be a positive thing.
NOTE CONF
If it's not a very positive culture, promotions are very
much around favoritism about who knows who and blah blah,
NOTE CONF
then this is going to be used as an excuse.
Right?
NOTE CONF
So it can do more harm than good.
Well, um, I strongly encourage you to, um, when you
NOTE CONF
go back to your Reading, studying pods that you consider
your original ideas and your changed ideas.
NOTE CONF
Um, as a summary of the summary, oh, by the
way, I should have said this, some people in the
NOTE CONF
subject think that we have lectures and have been saying,
hey, the lectures are too hurried, right?
NOTE CONF
There's no lectures in the subject, right?
This is a summary of the LMS which is the
NOTE CONF
LMS content is the lecture.
In the subject.
NOTE CONF
This is just a summary, right?
This is not a lecture.
NOTE CONF
So a lot of students, because the general, you know,
format in all subjects in this degree, MIS MIT is
NOTE CONF
you've got one lecture, and then you have tutorials.
They come to this subject and think it's the same.
NOTE CONF
We actually for quite a few years, did not have
any verbal, it was just the LMS and and tutorials.
NOTE CONF
And then students complained said, no, no, no, we need
face to face with the, so we, and I said
NOTE CONF
to my teaching team, I was like, you know, what's
gonna happen if I introduce a face to face like
NOTE CONF
this one, students are going to say, um, the lectures
are too short, right?
NOTE CONF
Because they're going to ignore the LMS and they're going
to focus on the lectures, which is what we're having
NOTE CONF
right now.
So just to remind everybody, there are no lectures in
NOTE CONF
the subject.
The primary delivery of material is the LMS content.
NOTE CONF
That is the subject content, which is the primary area
of content that you're going to be examined on.
NOTE CONF
This is just a summary to help you to get
through that, right?
NOTE CONF
So don't treat the LMS like it's yet another textbook.
The LMS is the main content, you're supposed to be
NOTE CONF
focused on that.
This is just to help you get through it.
NOTE CONF
If you're just coming here and looking at and listening
to what I'm saying, and ignoring the LMS, you're gonna
NOTE CONF
have a problem in the exam, right?
That's the main content.
NOTE CONF
This is just a summary.
Just to make sure that's clear.
NOTE CONF
OK, back to the program.
So, 3 things.
NOTE CONF
One program.
So you've got education, training and awareness.
NOTE CONF
Please, please, please know the distinctions between the three, and
how, where to use what.
NOTE CONF
7 steps to how to build a security training program.
So if we say on the exam, they build a
NOTE CONF
CETA program, we want to see the 7 steps.
You need to know how to do the steps, OK?
NOTE CONF
And make sure that you don't just say, here's the
program.
NOTE CONF
You've got to evaluate it and you've got to adapt
it to the culture, and culture is your biggest barrier,
NOTE CONF
the biggest monster you're fighting, right?
Culture, culture, culture, culture, not just in CETA, but in
NOTE CONF
every aspect of trying to create security programs and transform
an organization.
NOTE CONF
Culture is your biggest challenger.
You have to, you have to have a good strategy
NOTE CONF
around how to deal with culture.
And it's not just insecurity, it's anytime you want to
NOTE CONF
do anything and build a strategy and trying to get
the world to change, you have to deal with the
NOTE CONF
inertia of the world, which is why would the world
change.
NOTE CONF
OK, thank you very much and see you next week,
which I think is the last one before the mid-semester
NOTE CONF
break.
Fantastic, you then.
NOTE CONF
you.
What right just the tutors.
NOTE CONF
Thank you, yeah, yeah.
He, he should be on the same question with you.
NOTE CONF
OK.
Oh, same question.
NOTE CONF
I I'll finish it tomorrow.
know.
NOTE CONF
Yeah I haven't told you.
I Yeah.
NOTE CONF
Divided by